JUSTIN HART

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



847.340.4789



/justinhart90



/justinhart90



justinhart90@gmail



justin-hart.web.app



Denver, CO 80203

TECHNICAL TOOLS

Font End

Javascript (ES6+)

React.is

AngularJS

HTML5

CSS3

SASS

iQuery

D3.js

Redux

XML

Bootstrap

Back End

Node.js

ASP.NET Core

C#

SQL

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Express.js

Dev Ops

Git/Github

AWS

PWA

Ionic

Webpack

Gulp

npm

yarn

SUMMARY

Object-Oriented Analysis, Design and Development

Innovative software engineer with five years of Project Management experience and four years of experience in the full software development lifecycle – from concept through delivery - including continuous maintenance and support.

Experience building and supporting 25+ mobile and desktop applications, including advanced API integrations, with Fortune 500 companies.

Known for excellent troubleshooting skills – able to analyze code and engineer well-researched, cost-effective and responsive solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer, Rocky Mountain Devs LLC. Remote — 2019-Present

Utilize a diverse blend of business and software engineering experience to find creative solutions to client's problems.

Lead Solutions Engineer, JourneyApps

Denver, CO — 2018-2019

Managed an international development team, including weekly individual meetings with each member to coach, train, mentor and ensure their personal, professional and technical advancement.

Designed and implemented software solutions, including collecting requirements, engineering estimations, data modeling, UI/UX design, and the implementation of advanced external integrations including customer ERP/Financial systems.

Organized and led external client meetings and workshops; collaborated with executives, account managers and other technical stakeholders to continuously align technical capabilities with client needs.

Software Solutions Engineer, JourneyApps

Denver, CO - 2017-2018

Utilized a cloud-based app platform that included writing business logic in JavaScript, implementing extensible data models and building server-side integrations and data processing tasks using AWS Lambda and NodeJS.

Maintained a strong focus to deliver core value early, aiming to have a usable solution ready within 4 to 8 weeks.

Project Manager, Ricoh USA

Remote - 2012-2017

Configured and managed the implementation of a Professional Services Automation (PSA) tool that increased operational efficiency by automating processes, discovering new business intelligence through internal reporting, and reducing how many employees are needed for a project. Earned the RICOH Way Award in 2016 for achievements in innovation and automation.

EDUCATION

Galvanize Inc — Denver, Platte

2017

Full Stack Web Development (24-week immersive program)

Project Management Institute — Denver, CO

2013

PMI Certified Associate in Project Management

University of Colorado at Boulder — Leeds School of Business

2008-2012

Bachelor of Science (BS), Business Administration, Finance